const quizQuestions18en = [{
    question:"Regarding electroslag welding (ESW), it is correct to say:",
    answers: ["Heat is generated by passing current through the weld pool.",
    "It is possible to weld sections over 20 cm thick.",
    "Shoes are unnecessary for this process when the sheets are positioned horizontally.",
    "The ESW process is very economical as it can take advantage of the flux used in SAW process (but it must be of the active type)."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Compared to the solid wire MIG/MAG process, flux cored wire welding (FCAW) can offer:",
    answers: ["better base metal wettability when welding aluminium alloys;",
    "better base metal wettability when welding stainless steels;",
    "lower spatter generation;",
    "a possibility of welding thinner sheets."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Compared to the solid wire MIG/MAG process, flux cored wire welding (FCAW) can offer:",
    answers: ["better base metal wettability when welding aluminium alloys;",
    "lower spatter generation;",
    "a possibility of welding thinner sheets;",
    "higher penetration."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Among these processes used in additive manufacturing, which is the most suitable for building a valve in the shape of a hollow tube with a diameter of 10 mm and a thickness of 2 mm?",
    answers: ["GTAW (TIG welding).",
    "GMAW (MIG/MAG welding).",
    " Laser directed energy deposition (L-DED).",
    "Selective Laser Melting."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"It is a characteristic of robotic MIG/MAG welding application:",
    answers: ["The deposition rate becomes higher.",
    "Reduction of manufacturing costs, especially in smaller-scale production.",
    "The robot can perform some welds that are impossible for a welder to perform.",
    "Non-productive time is reduced as the robot can be operated 24 hours a day."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"It is a characteristic of robotic MIG/MAG welding application:",
    answers: ["The deposition rate becomes higher.",
    "Robot application efficiency is lower when the robot is programmed on-line for short welds.",
    "Reduction of manufacturing costs, especially in smaller-scale production.",
    "The robot can perform some welds that are impossible for a welder to perform."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"It is a characteristic of robotic MIG/MAG welding application:",
    answers: ["The deposition rate becomes higher.",
    "Reduction of manufacturing costs, especially in smaller-scale production.",
    "It is desirable that the joint be redesigned for robotic welding.",
    "The robot can perform some welds that are impossible for a welder to perform."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"The laser (LBW) and electron beam (EBW) welding processes are characterized by the following characteristic:",
    answers: ["They tolerate large root gaps between sheets to be welded.",
    "They offer a high penetration/width ratio.",
    "They are easily handled during manual welding.",
    "They use a more expensive filler metal."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"The lobe curve (Current x Time) in resistance spot welding represents:",
    answers: ["A function between the current value in the primary and the duration of the alternating current half-cycle.",
    "A function between the current value in the secondary and the duration of the alternating current half-cycle.",
    "A relationship between welding current and welding time at which acceptable quality welding points are obtained.",
    "A relationship between current and welding time with the same energy generated (the same heat generated)."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"In the case of SAW process with a Constant Voltage power source, the operator has reached the limit of the wire feed speed of the equipment. How to increase the current even more?",
    answers: ["To increase the contact tip-to-work distance (if allowed by EPS) while continuing to use the maximum wire feed speed.",
    "To reduce the contact tip-to-work distance (if allowed by EPS), while still using the maximum wire feed speed.",
    "To change the wire to a smaller diameter (if allowed by EPS), continuing to use the maximum wire feed speed.",
    "Increase the no-load voltage of the power source, maintaining the same arc voltage."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"In the case of SAW process with a Constant Voltage power source, the operator has reached the limit of the wire feed speed of the equipment. How to increase the current even more?",
    answers: ["To increase the contact tip-to-work distance (if allowed by EPS) while continuing to use the maximum wire feed speed.",
    "To change the wire to a smaller diameter (if allowed by EPS), continuing to use the maximum wire feed speed.",
    "To change the wire for a larger diameter (if allowed by EPS), reducing the wire feed speed to the appropriate value.",
    "Increase the no-load voltage of the power source, maintaining the same arc voltage."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding the weldability of galvanized (zinc plated) sheets when using resistance spot welding, it can be stated that:",
    answers: ["The burning of zinc in galvanized sheets (burn-zinc operation) is achieved by using a cycle with high current (above the level of the welding current) for a short time before making the spot weld.",
    "The zinc layers do not present any difficulty, because, thanks to a low melting and boiling points, the zinc evaporates before the melting point of the steel is reached.",
    "One of the advantages of resistance welding galvanized sheets is a good electrical contact between the sheets.",
    "The burning of zinc (burn-zinc operation) is achieved applying a low current pulse for a short time before making the spot weld."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding the Plasma arc welding process (PAW) it is correct to state that:",
    answers: ["Current is the main factor to ensure the physical constriction of the arc (narrow, columnar profile of the arc).",
    "The constricting nozzle orifice diameter is one of the main factors for increasing the plasma jet velocity.",
    "A high flow rate of plasma gas is the main factor in ensuring the physical constriction of the arc (narrow columnar profile of the arc).",
    "A high arc voltage is one of the main factors for increasing plasma jet speed."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding the Plasma arc welding process (PAW) it is correct to state that:",
    answers: ["Current is the main factor to ensure the physical constriction of the arc (narrow, columnar profile of the arc).",
    "A high flow rate of plasma gas is the main factor in ensuring the physical constriction of the arc (narrow columnar profile of the arc).",
    "A high arc voltage is one of the main factors for increasing plasma jet speed.",
    "Plasma gas is typically of a low flow rate, in the order of 0.25 to 5 l/min."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Comparing the electroslag (ESW) and electrogas (EGW) processes, it is possible to state that:",
    answers: ["The electrogas process requires a slightly more complex shoe, as it needs to provide for the inlet and distribution of the shielding gas, in addition to cooling.",
    "Only the electroslag process generates large columnar grains and extensive HAZ, as the energy is less concentrated.",
    "The electroslag process requires gas to protect the slag against atmospheric oxidation.",
    "The ESW process can only be used in the flat position, while the EGW process can be applied in any welding position."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Comparing the electroslag (ESW) and electrogas (EGW) processes, it is possible to state that:",
    answers: ["Only the electroslag process generates large columnar grains and extensive HAZ, as the energy is less concentrated.",
    "One of the limitations of the electrogas process is the logistics of having the necessary shielding gas for the process.",
    "The electroslag process requires gas to protect the slag against atmospheric oxidation.",
    "The ESW process can only be used in the flat position, while the EGW process can be applied in any welding position."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding the Stud Welding (SW) process, it is correct to say:",
    answers: ["There are two versions of the SW process: Capacitor Discharge Stud Welding and Resistance Stud Welding.",
    "The process has a low execution time, taking on average less than 1 s, from the positioning of the gun until the stud is released.",
    "It is not possible to weld dissimilar materials.",
    "An important advantage of the process is that the stud can be welded onto painted and galvanized surfaces."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding the Stud Welding (SW) process, it is correct to say:",
    answers: ["There are two versions of the SW process: Capacitor Discharge Stud Welding and Resistance Stud Welding.",
    "It is not possible to weld dissimilar materials.",
    "There are two versions of this process: Arc Stud Welding and Capacitor Discharge Stud Welding.",
    "An important advantage of the process is that the stud can be welded onto painted and galvanized surfaces."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding the Stud Welding (SW) process, it is correct to say:",
    answers: ["There are two versions of the SW process: Capacitor Discharge Stud Welding and Resistance Stud Welding.",
    "It is not possible to weld dissimilar materials.",
    "An important advantage of the process is that the stud can be welded onto painted and galvanized surfaces.",
    "The stud can be circular or rectangular in profile and can be hollow or solid, ranging from heavy support studs to spacer studs."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"What would you do if you need to reduce penetration in MIG/MAG welding?",
    answers: ["I would reduce the arc voltage.",
    "\"I would change the welding technique from \"\"forehand\"\" (\"\"pushing\"\") to \"\"backhand\"\" (\"\"pulling\"\").\"",
    "It would increase the contact tip-to-work distance.",
    "I would change the shielding gas to a CO2-rich mixture."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"About the high frequency resistance welding process, it is correct to state:",
    answers: ["There are two versions of this process depending on the method of generating the high frequency current in the parts to be welded: the current is introduced by sliding electrodes or the current is induced by an induction coil.",
    "High frequency resistance welding is classified as a fusion welding process.",
    "The maximum frequency applied in induction welding does not exceed 50 kHz.",
    "\"One of the disadvantages of this welding process is that the high frequency current tends to concentrate on the outer surface of the conductor (\"\"skin effect\"\"), thus reducing the efficiency of heating the base metal.\""],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"About the high frequency resistance welding process, it is correct to state:",
    answers: ["High frequency resistance welding is classified as a fusion welding process.",
    "Butt and corner joints can be welded by this process.",
    "The maximum frequency applied in induction welding does not exceed 50 kHz.",
    "\"One of the disadvantages of this welding process is that the high frequency current tends to concentrate on the outer surface of the conductor (\"\"skin effect\"\"), thus reducing the efficiency of heating the base metal.\""],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"About the high frequency resistance welding process, it is correct to state:",
    answers: ["High frequency resistance welding is classified as a fusion welding process.",
    "The maximum frequency applied in induction welding does not exceed 50 kHz.",
    "In the case of induction welding, the higher the frequency imposed, the smaller the current conduction zone obtained in the part, thus increasing the current density.",
    "\"One of the disadvantages of this welding process is that the high frequency current tends to concentrate on the outer surface of the conductor (\"\"skin effect\"\"), thus reducing the efficiency of heating the base metal.\""],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"About the high frequency resistance welding process, it is correct to state:",
    answers: ["High frequency resistance welding is classified as a fusion welding process.",
    "The maximum frequency applied in induction welding does not exceed 50 kHz.",
    "\"One of the disadvantages of this welding process is that the high frequency current tends to concentrate on the outer surface of the conductor (\"\"skin effect\"\"), thus reducing the efficiency of heating the base metal.\"",
    "\"The name of this method can be added by \"\"induction\"\", if the current is induced by an induction coil.\""],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Mark the correct statements regarding the thermal spraying processes.",
    answers: ["The basic variations of thermal spraying processes occur in the materials used, in the heating method and in the method of propelling the materials to the substrate.",
    "Substrate preparation (surface cleaning) is basically done by cathodic cleaning.",
    "Thermally sprayed coatings never receive post-spray treatments.",
    "The joining between the coating and the substrate is basically a mechanical anchoring bonding."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Mark the correct statements regarding the thermal spraying processes.",
    answers: ["Substrate preparation (surface cleaning) is basically done by cathodic cleaning.",
    "Substrate preparation prior to spraying is required for all process variations and the two important steps are cleaning the surface and generating adequate roughness.",
    "Thermally sprayed coatings never receive post-spray treatments.",
    "The joining between the coating and the substrate is basically a mechanical anchoring bonding."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Mark the correct statements regarding the thermal spraying processes.",
    answers: ["Substrate preparation (surface cleaning) is basically done by cathodic cleaning.",
    "Thermally sprayed coatings never receive post-spray treatments.",
    "The bond between the coating and the substrate is influenced by factors such as the surface temperature before, during and after spraying and particle impact velocity.",
    "The joining between the coating and the substrate is basically a mechanical anchoring bonding."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Mark the correct statements regarding the thermal spraying processes.",
    answers: ["Substrate preparation (surface cleaning) is basically done by cathodic cleaning.",
    "Thermally sprayed coatings never receive post-spray treatments.",
    "The joining between the coating and the substrate is basically a mechanical anchoring bonding.",
    "The bond between the coating and the substrate may be mechanical, chemical, metallurgical, physical or a combination of these."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Mark the correct statements regarding the thermal spraying processes.",
    answers: ["Substrate preparation (surface cleaning) is basically done by cathodic cleaning.",
    "Thermally sprayed coatings never receive post-spray treatments.",
    "The bond between the coating and the substrate is influenced by factors such as coating material, substrate condition, degree of surface roughness and cleanliness.",
    "The joining between the coating and the substrate is basically a mechanical anchoring bonding."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"This is a characteristic of electronic power sources, mainly of the inverter type, but not of electromagnetic power sources (transformer-rectifiers):",
    answers: ["High frequency arc striking.",
    "The easiness of interfacing with automatic equipment.",
    "They allow to increase the welding current (for example, from 100 A to 120 A) without causing an increase in the energy consumption of the supply network.",
    "Inductance adjustment."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"This is a characteristic of electronic power sources, mainly of the inverter type, but not of electromagnetic power sources (transformer-rectifiers):",
    answers: ["High frequency arc striking.",
    "They allow to increase the welding current (for example, from 100 A to 120 A) without causing an increase in the energy consumption of the supply network.",
    "Inductance adjustment.",
    "They consume less energy from the supply network working at the same level of welding current."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding the particularity of supplying filler metal in the submerged arc welding (SAW) process, mark the correct alternative:",
    answers: ["The filler metal is supplied in the form of solid or tubular wires, through single or multiple electrode configurations, as well as, in special techniques (in surfacing), in the form of metallic strip.",
    "In the SAW process, in special applications, filler metal can be additionally supplied in the form of iron powder, which is mixed with the flux before the flux is applied.",
    "In SAW welding, the cold wire addition technique is not applicable due to the risk of generating metallic inclusions.",
    "The hot wire addition technique works well, but only if those wires are thin (in the range of 1.0 - 1.2 mm)."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"It is an advantage of brazing/soldering joining over fusion welding:",
    answers: ["Make it possible to carry out any type of joint (but, lap, Tee, Edge and Corner joint).",
    "More heat, but lower temperature are required than in welding by the same heating method.",
    "Filler metal is of lower cost.",
    "Ability to preserve coatings on the base metal (without burning)."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"It is an advantage of brazing/soldering joining over fusion welding:",
    answers: ["Make it possible to carry out any type of joint (but, lap, Tee, Edge and Corner joint);",
    "Ability to join metals with non-metallic materials;",
    "More heat, but lower temperature are required than in welding by the same heating method;",
    "Filler metal is of lower cost."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Mark the true alternative regarding welding processes:",
    answers: ["In electroslag welding (ESW), the shoes must be of the same material as the plates to be welded, to ensure uniformity of the joint.",
    "By electroslag welding (ESW), it is possible to weld sections of large thickness (higher than 30 mm) in the flat position (vertical upwards progression or approximately to this).",
    "In Friction Stir Welding, the tool is consumed as the weld is being performed.",
    "In electrogas welding (EGW), the shoes must be of the same metal as the workpieces, as they form part of the joint."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Mark the true alternative regarding welding processes:",
    answers: ["In electroslag welding (ESW), the shoes must be of the same material as the plates to be welded, to ensure uniformity of the joint.",
    "In Friction Stir Welding, the tool is consumed as the weld is being performed.",
    "In electrogas welding (EGW), the shoes must be of the same material as the plates to be welded, as they form part of the joint.",
    "Friction welding is based on frictional relative motion between parts, that is, one can be immobile."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding filler metals for brazing/soldering, mark the correct statement:",
    answers: ["Generally speaking, a short melting temperature range filler metal is more suitable for large gap joints.",
    "Copper alloys (e.g., copper-zinc) are used in joining all ferrous and non-ferrous materials, in lap or butt joints, with different heating methods.",
    "Gold and its alloys are used for brazing iron, nickel and cobalt when oxidation resistance is required or in applications where volatile components are undesirable.",
    "The most suitable filler metal for soldering is lead."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding filler metals for brazing/soldering, mark the correct statement:",
    answers: ["Silver-based filler metals are used for joining many ferrous and non-ferrous metals and can be used with all heating methods.",
    "Generally speaking, a short melting temperature range filler metal is more suitable for large gap joints.",
    "Copper alloys (e.g., copper-zinc) are used in joining all ferrous and non-ferrous materials, in lap or butt joints, with different heating methods.",
    "The most suitable filler metal for soldering is lead."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"It is a typical characteristic of Hot Gas Welding of Plastics:",
    answers: ["The most commonly used in this process are compressed air, nitrogen, hydrogen, oxygen and carbon dioxide.",
    "Welding consists of blowing a stream of heated gas over the surface to be welded until it begins to melt. Then, the thermoplastic welding rod is forced into the molten pool, thus promoting welding.",
    "Type, temperature and gas flow rate, the angle formed between the filler rod and the base material and the welding speed are the process variables to be controlled.",
    "Type, temperature and gas flow rate, as well as the feeding speed are the process variables to be controlled."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"It is a typical characteristic of Hot Gas Welding of Plastics:",
    answers: ["The joint design is similar to that used in filler arc welding and includes butt, corner and lap joints, which are bevelled in the same manner as metals.",
    "The most commonly used in this process are compressed air, nitrogen, hydrogen, oxygen and carbon dioxide.",
    "Welding consists of blowing a stream of heated gas over the surface to be welded until it begins to melt. Then, the thermoplastic welding rod is forced into the molten pool, thus promoting welding.",
    "Type, temperature and gas flow rate, as well as the feeding speed are the process variables to be controlled."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"It is a typical characteristic of Hot Gas Welding of Plastics:",
    answers: ["The most commonly used in this process are compressed air, nitrogen, hydrogen, oxygen and carbon dioxide.",
    "Welding consists of blowing a stream of heated gas, usually air, to heat and melt both the thermoplastic substrate material and the thermoplastic welding rod. Then the filler material is forced into the joint, thus promoting welding.",
    "Welding consists of blowing a stream of heated gas over the surface to be welded until it begins to melt. Then, the thermoplastic welding rod is forced into the molten pool, thus promoting welding.",
    "Type, temperature and gas flow rate, as well as the feeding speed are the process variables to be controlled."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Mark the correct alternative with regard to welding plastics.",
    answers: ["Ultrasonic welding is indicated for joining large parts.",
    "Increased productivity in hot plate welding is achieved by employing higher temperatures and longer heating times.",
    "Fusion welding processes are the most suitable for welding plastics.",
    "When welding with hot gas, the welding plastic rod must not be melted completely."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Mark the correct alternative in relation to sensors used in automatic welding:",
    answers: ["Sensors based on the arc electrical signal (voltage or current), so called “through-the-arc sensors”, are used for both joint tracking and for the contact tip-to-work distance control.",
    "Contact sensors for joint tracking (joint trackers) cannot be used in fusion welding as heat damages them.",
    "The laser to be used as a sensor in welding must be of the Nd:YAG or CO2 type.",
    "The heat produced by the arc and spatter do not pose any risk to the correct operation of the sensors in welding."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Mark the correct alternative in relation to sensors used in automatic welding:",
    answers: ["Contact sensors for joint tracking (joint trackers) cannot be used in fusion welding as heat damages them.",
    "The laser sensor can be used effectively for both joint tracking and to evaluate the groove geometry/joint surface.",
    "The laser to be used as a sensor in welding must be of the Nd:YAG or CO2 type.",
    "The heat produced by the arc and spatter do not pose any risk to the correct operation of the sensors in welding."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"It is an advantage of the FCAW process over the GMAW process using the same gas CO2:",
    answers: ["Lower spatter generation.",
    "Lower electrode metal losses from its burning.",
    "The wire feeder can be made simpler (with just two rollers).",
    "Welding in all positions."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"It is an advantage of the FCAW process over the GMAW process using the same gas CO2:",
    answers: ["Lower electrode metal losses from its burning.",
    "Improved weld geometry.",
    "The wire feeder can be made simpler (with just two rollers).",
    "Welding in all positions."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"It is an advantage of the FCAW process over the GMAW process using the same gas CO2:",
    answers: ["Lower electrode metal losses from its burning.",
    "The wire feeder can be made simpler (with just two rollers).",
    "Welding in all positions.",
    "Higher porosity resistance of the weld metal."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding the welding process with tubular wires (MIG/MAG “metal cored”) and with tubular electrodes (flux cored arc welding, FCAW) it is correct to say that:",
    answers: ["There are two basic variations of the FCAW with tubular wires (metal-cored), namely, with and without external gas shielding.",
    "In semi-automatic welding with tubular wires and tubular electrodes, it is highly recommended to use 4 rollers in the electrode wire feeding system.",
    "For the FCAW process it is necessary to use wire feeders and torches developed specifically for that.",
    "Because of difficulties in manufacturing tubular wires and electrodes, their diameters are 1.6 mm and higher (while solid wire diameters are usually within the range of 0.6 to 1.6 mm)."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"In resistance welding, it is correct to state that:",
    answers: ["In projection welding, the shape of the electrodes must conform to the shape of the projections.",
    "In resistance butt welding, the pressure is increased after the current is turned off, which causes an excess of material in the joint region.",
    "The pressure in spot welding must be as low as possible, as its function is to just position the parts (high pressure reduces the electrical resistance and, therefore, the heating at the interface).",
    "The pressure in spot welding should be high, as its function is to forge the parts after the current is turned off."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"It is one of the advantages of direct current power sources over alternating current power sources for resistance spot welding:",
    answers: ["They are larger and therefore more robust.",
    "They charge all three phases of the power network equally (whereas AC power sources use only two phases).",
    "They offer better control of penetration (it is higher on the negative electrode side).",
    "They offer better control of penetration (it is higher on the positive electrode side)."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"It is one of the advantages of direct current power sources over alternating current power sources for resistance spot welding:",
    answers: ["They are larger and therefore more robust.",
    "They offer better control of penetration (it is higher on the negative electrode side).",
    "They offer better control of penetration (it is higher on the positive electrode side).",
    "They offer better dynamic control, as the adjustment time is in ms and not in cycles, making it possible to better discretize the times."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Mark the true alternative, regarding the brazing/soldering process:",
    answers: ["There is no brazing/soldering without using the capillary effect.",
    "Brazing with a silver alloy, despite its lower mechanical strength, is often preferable to brazing with a Cu-Zn (brass) or Cu-Sn (bronze) alloy, as it has a lower melting point.",
    "The larger the gap, the easier the capillary effect and the higher the strength of the brazed joint.",
    "Aluminium, as it has a low melting point, cannot be brazed."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following statements is true regarding the plasma welding process?",
    answers: ["One of the properties of plasma gases that can influence the performance of plasma welding is their chemical reactivity (only inert or reducing gases can be used).",
    "In plasma welding, direct current with electrode negative polarity is always applied to all materials.",
    "Current is the main factor to ensure the physical constriction of the arc (narrow, columnar profile of the arc).",
    "In general, it is the diameter of the constrictor hole that determines the arc concentration, so the electrode sharpening angle and its distance from the face of the constrictor nozzle hole are not important parameters."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following statements is true regarding the plasma welding process?",
    answers: ["In plasma welding, direct current with electrode negative polarity is always applied to all materials.",
    "An increase in current leads to higher width and penetration of the weld bead.",
    "Current is the main factor to ensure the physical constriction of the arc (narrow, columnar profile of the arc).",
    "In general, it is the diameter of the constrictor hole that determines the arc concentration, so the electrode sharpening angle and its distance from the face of the constrictor nozzle hole are not important parameters."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following statements is true regarding the plasma welding process?",
    answers: ["In plasma welding, direct current with electrode negative polarity is always applied to all materials.",
    "Current is the main factor to ensure the physical constriction of the arc (narrow, columnar profile of the arc).",
    "In general, a reduction in the diameter of the constrictor orifice increases the concentration and pressure of the arc and, therefore, the penetration capacity.",
    "In general, it is the diameter of the constrictor hole that determines the arc concentration, so the electrode sharpening angle and its distance from the face of the constrictor nozzle hole are not important parameters."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Which of the following statements is true regarding the plasma welding process?",
    answers: ["In plasma welding, direct current with electrode negative polarity is always applied to all materials.",
    "Current is the main factor to ensure the physical constriction of the arc (narrow, columnar profile of the arc).",
    "The sharpening of the electrode in the Plasma process facilitates the emission of electrons by thermionic effect (higher heating for having less volume).",
    "In general, it is the diameter of the constrictor hole that determines the arc concentration, so the electrode sharpening angle and its distance from the face of the constrictor nozzle hole are not important parameters."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding the classification of welding processes into “fusion” and “solid state” welding, mark the correct alternative:",
    answers: ["In the processes classified as “Solid State Welding”, the phenomenon of diffusion has high importance.",
    "In order to have welding joining, it is always necessary to have an imposed thermal energy, except for the processes classified as “Solid State Welding”.",
    "\"The pressure, consequently the friction, is the driving force to generate the heat to carry out the welding of the processes classified as \"\"Solid State Welding\"\".\"",
    "All welding processes classified as “Fusion Welding” use the arc as the heat source."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"The following is one of the advantages of Pulsed MIG welding:",
    answers: ["Possibility of using pure CO2 as a shielding gas.",
    "Possibility of using a large diameter wire electrode to weld thin sheets.",
    "High deposition rate.",
    "Higher penetration due to the mechanical action of the current pulse."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding the Friction Stir Welding, the following statement is true:",
    answers: ["A rotating non-consumable tool is inserted between two facing workpieces to promote heating and coalescence.",
    "For thin sheets, it can be carried out in the semi-automatic version, with the rotating tool attached to a drill translated along the joint by the welder.",
    "A high degree plastic deformation imposed in the joint region causes distortions and very high residual stresses.",
    "\"In this welding process, there are no weld defect of the \"\"lack of fusion\"\" type, as the rotating tool softens both edges of the joint evenly.\""],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding the Friction Stir Welding, the following statement is true:",
    answers: ["For thin sheets, it can be carried out in the semi-automatic version, with the rotating tool attached to a drill translated along the joint by the welder.",
    "It is a solid-state welding process (less heat input), normally with full penetration.",
    "A high degree plastic deformation imposed in the joint region causes distortions and very high residual stresses.",
    "\"In this welding process, there are no weld defect of the \"\"lack of fusion\"\" type, as the rotating tool softens both edges of the joint evenly.\""],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding the Friction Stir Welding, the following statement is true:",
    answers: ["For thin sheets, it can be carried out in the semi-automatic version, with the rotating tool attached to a drill translated along the joint by the welder.",
    "A high degree plastic deformation imposed in the joint region causes distortions and very high residual stresses.",
    "No consumables and shielding gases are used in the process.",
    "\"In this welding process, there are no weld defect of the \"\"lack of fusion\"\" type, as the rotating tool softens both edges of the joint evenly.\""],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding arc welding surfacing techniques, it is correct to say that:",
    answers: ["Hardfacing is carried out only by coated electrode, as other processes cannot deposit the necessary alloying elements.",
    "Buttering is a coating operation whose function is to protect the surface against corrosion.",
    "Stainless steel layers are deposited on carbon steel substrate surfaces not to maintain the structural properties of the substrate, but to increase its corrosion resistance.",
    "The tubular electrode process is widely used for hardfacing, but only with a gas shielding, to minimize the losses of the alloying elements."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Mark the correct alternative in relation to sensors, actuators and controllers used in mechanized and automated (robotized) welding processes.",
    answers: ["Actuators are components that convert electrical, hydraulic or pneumatic energy into mechanical energy.",
    "Actuators are components that convert mechanical, hydraulic or pneumatic energy into electrical energy.",
    "The sensor receives an electrical signal or stimulus (input signal) and responds with a mechanical signal (output signal).",
    "In an automatic system, the controller receives signals from actuators and controls the operation of sensors."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Mark the correct alternative in relation to sensors, actuators and controllers used in mechanized and automated (robotized) welding processes.",
    answers: ["Actuators are components that convert mechanical, hydraulic or pneumatic energy into electrical energy.",
    "Sensors provide the control unit with information about the behaviour of the automatic system.",
    "The sensor receives an electrical signal or stimulus (input signal) and responds with a mechanical signal (output signal).",
    "In an automatic system, the controller receives signals from actuators and controls the operation of sensors."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Mark the correct alternative in relation to sensors, actuators and controllers used in mechanized and automated (robotized) welding processes.",
    answers: ["Actuators are components that convert mechanical, hydraulic or pneumatic energy into electrical energy.",
    "The sensor receives an electrical signal or stimulus (input signal) and responds with a mechanical signal (output signal).",
    "Controllers are responsible for managing and monitoring the operating parameters required for the automatic system to carry out the expected tasks.",
    "In an automatic system, the controller receives signals from actuators and controls the operation of sensors."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Mark the correct alternative in relation to sensors, actuators and controllers used in mechanized and automated (robotized) welding processes.",
    answers: ["Actuators are components that convert mechanical, hydraulic or pneumatic energy into electrical energy.",
    "The sensor receives an electrical signal or stimulus (input signal) and responds with a mechanical signal (output signal).",
    "In an automatic system, the controller receives signals from actuators and controls the operation of sensors.",
    "The movement commands coming from controllers and sent to the actuators are originated in the control unit and based on information obtained by the sensors."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Mark the correct alternative in relation to sensors, actuators and controllers used in mechanized and automated (robotized) welding processes.",
    answers: ["The sensor receives a signal or stimulus (input signal that can be: presence or absence of light, heat, sound, gas, electric field, magnetic field, etc.) and responds with an electrical output signal.",
    "Actuators are components that convert mechanical, hydraulic or pneumatic energy into electrical energy.",
    "The sensor receives an electrical signal or stimulus (input signal) and responds with a mechanical signal (output signal).",
    "In an automatic system, the controller receives signals from actuators and controls the operation of sensors."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding the particularity of supplying filler metal in the submerged arc welding (SAW) process, mark the correct alternative:",
    answers: ["The filler metal can be additionally supplied in the form of iron powder, which is mixed with the flux before its use.",
    "In SAW welding, the cold wire addition technique is not applicable due to the risk of generating metallic inclusions.",
    "In configurations with two electrode wires, they can be placed next to each other in a line perpendicular to the joint line (Twin Arc) or one behind the other in the welding direction (Tandem Arc).",
    "The hot wire addition technique works well in SAW welding, but only if those wires are thin (in the range of 1.0 - 1.2 mm) so as not to harm the metallurgy of the process."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding the particularity of supplying filler metal in the submerged arc welding (SAW) process, mark the correct alternative:",
    answers: ["The filler metal can be additionally supplied in the form of iron powder, which is mixed with the flux before its use.",
    "In SAW welding, the cold wire addition technique is not applicable due to the risk of generating metallic inclusions.",
    "The hot wire addition technique works well in SAW welding, but only if those wires are thin (in the range of 1.0 - 1.2 mm) so as not to harm the metallurgy of the process.",
    "For the SAW process, electrode wires with a diameter of 1.6 to 6.4 mm are used, the most common being 2.4 mm, 3.25 mm and 4.0 mm."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding the particularity of supplying filler metal in the submerged arc welding (SAW) process, mark the correct alternative:",
    answers: ["The filler metal can be additionally supplied in the form of iron powder, which is mixed with the flux before its use.",
    "In special applications of the SAW, the filler metal can be supplied additionally in the form of iron powder layer placed above the joint line before the flux (i.e., below the flux).",
    "In SAW welding, the cold wire addition technique is not applicable due to the risk of generating metallic inclusions.",
    "The hot wire addition technique works well in SAW welding, but only if those wires are thin (in the range of 1.0 - 1.2 mm) so as not to harm the metallurgy of the process."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Mark the correct alternative with regard to welding plastics.",
    answers: ["Ultrasonic welding is indicated for joining large parts.",
    "Thermosets are easily weldable.",
    "In hot gas welding, the joint design is similar to that used in welding of metals with a filler material.",
    "Fusion welding processes are the most suitable for welding plastics."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Mark the correct alternative with regard to welding plastics.",
    answers: ["Polymers are classified according to their behaviour at high temperatures and their chain structure.",
    "Thermosets are easily weldable.",
    "Fusion welding processes are the most suitable for welding plastics.",
    "Increased productivity in hot plate welding is achieved by employing higher temperatures and longer heating times."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"0 "
    },
     {
    question:"Regarding the classification of polymers, it is possible to state:",
    answers: ["Polymers are divided into plastics, thermosets and duroplastics.",
    "Polymers are divided into elastomers, thermosets and polyplastics.",
    "Polymers are divided into elastomers, thermosets and thermoplastics.",
    "Polymers are divided into elastomers, thermosets and duroplastics."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"0 "},
    {
    question:"What microalloying addition is made to steel to make it possible to eliminate the coarse grain region in the heat affected zone immediately adjacent to the fusion line?",
    answers: ["Titanium.",
    "Aluminium.",
    "Copper.",
    "Molybdenum."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"It is correct to say that the TTT diagrams of C-Mn steels:",
    answers: ["are used to predict the microstructures that appear during continuous cooling conditions;",
    "are used to predict the equilibrium structure of steels;",
    "are affected by the chemical composition of the steels;",
    "can be shifted to the left by alloying elements."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"It is correct to say that the TTT diagrams of C-Mn steels:",
    answers: ["are used to predict the microstructures that appear during continuous cooling conditions;",
    "are used to predict the equilibrium structure of steels;",
    "are used to estimate the amount of bainite and martensite in the microstructure;",
    "can be shifted to the left by alloying elements."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"After welding Cr-Mo steel, optimum properties can be achieved by:",
    answers: ["stress relieving;",
    "tempering;",
    "quenching and tempering;",
    "normalising, but the HAZ only."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"One of the most important factors for an efficient thermomechanical treatment of steels is:",
    answers: ["higher cooling rate to reduce grain size even further;",
    "higher temperature than in the conventional hot rolling process;",
    "lower cooling rate to reduce grain size even further;",
    "deformation rate lower than in the conventional hot rolling process."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"One of the most important factors for an efficient thermomechanical treatment of steels is:",
    answers: ["addition of Nb (approx. 0.05%);",
    "higher temperature than in the conventional hot rolling process;",
    "lower cooling rate to reduce grain size even further;",
    "deformation rate lower than in the conventional hot rolling process."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Mark the correct alternative regarding the factors that influence the choice of filler metal for welding aluminium and its alloys:",
    answers: ["Chemical composition of the base metal;",
    "Electrode wire feeding technique in the MIG process when welding is carried out with a torch length greater than 8 m;",
    "Base metal tendency to fatigue crack phenomenon;",
    "The HAZ size and its ductility."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Mark the correct alternative regarding the factors that influence the choice of filler metal for welding aluminium and its alloys:",
    answers: ["Base metal tendency to fatigue crack phenomenon;",
    "Electrode wire feeding technique in the MIG process when welding is carried out with a torch length greater than 8 m;",
    "Base metal tendency to solidification cracking phenomenon;",
    "The HAZ size and its ductility."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"In relation to the welding of low carbon steels with 9% Ni doubly normalized and annealed, it is correct to state that:",
    answers: ["The use of the consumable E308L with 19% Cr and 9% Ni is adequate because it has a coefficient of thermal expansion close to that of the base metal.",
    "Consumables composed of alloys with high nickel content are indicated by having a coefficient of thermal expansion close to that of the base metal, reducing the risk of failure due to thermal fatigue.",
    "Due to a low hardenability of the base metal, martensite formation in the HAZ is not common even at high cooling rates.",
    "Martensitic consumables are adequate for having a coefficient of thermal expansion close to that of the base metal."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"It is one of the typical stages of the fracture process:",
    answers: ["Growth of internal stresses;",
    "Crack nucleation;",
    "Abrupt increase in compressive stresses;",
    "Metastable crack growth."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"It is one of the typical stages of the fracture process:",
    answers: ["Growth of internal stresses;",
    "Stable crack growth;",
    "Abrupt increase in compressive stresses;",
    "Metastable crack growth."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"It is one of the typical stages of the fracture process:",
    answers: ["Growth of internal stresses;",
    "Unstable crack growth (final break);",
    "Abrupt increase in compressive stresses;",
    "Metastable crack growth."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the analysis of the fracture surface of a steel component, it can be stated:",
    answers: ["A shiny fracture surface indicates a ductile failure with macroscopic plastic deformation;",
    "Radial marks indicate the unstable growth stage of the fracture;",
    "Radial marks or river marks indicate the fracture initiation site;",
    "Beach marks indicate the final stage of unstable fracture growth."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the analysis of the fracture surface of a steel component, it can be stated:",
    answers: ["A shiny fracture surface indicates a ductile failure with macroscopic plastic deformation;",
    "Radial marks indicate the unstable growth stage of the fracture;",
    "Shear zone forms near the surface of the part and occurs under plane stress conditions;",
    "Beach marks indicate the final stage of unstable fracture growth."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"The thermochemical cementation treatment consists of:",
    answers: ["the introduction of nitrogen into carbon steel, so that, after quenching, it has a hard surface;",
    "the introduction of carbon into stainless steel, so that, after quenching, it has a hard surface;",
    "the introduction of nitrogen into stainless steel, so that, after quenching, it has a hard surface;",
    "the introduction of carbon into carbon steel, so that, after quenching, it has a hard surface."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"About the thermochemical treatment of cementation (carburizing) it is correct to say:",
    answers: ["The liquid carburizing technique consists of keeping the steel in a bath of molten salt at a temperature below the A1 line of the Fe-C diagram for a given time.",
    "In gas carburizing technique the part is placed in a furnace with a controlled carbon-rich atmosphere.",
    "In vacuum carburizing technique the part is placed in a vacuum chamber with subsequent injection of nitrogen gas.",
    "The plasma carburizing technique consists of treating the part surface by a plasma thermal spray torch with CO2 gas."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Thermochemical treatments aim to:",
    answers: ["increase surface hardness and wear resistance, keeping the material core ductile;",
    "obtain products with high ductility and impact resistance, without significant loss of hardness;",
    "increase the limit of tensile strength of carbon steel and its hardness;",
    "reduce steel hardness, increase machinability, facilitate cold working."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding fine-grained steels, it is correct to say:",
    answers: ["All fine-grained steels have martensitic HAZ, due to the greater hardenability of a fine-grained material;",
    "The heat treatment for grain refining is done by austenization and rapid cooling (in water or oil), to prevent grain growth;",
    "The annealing heat treatment is not used for the refining of grains;",
    "The steels, which fine-grained structure is obtained by normalizing, have greater toughness and yield limit than annealed steels of the same composition."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Typical means of obtaining fine-grained structural steels are:",
    answers: ["High content of alloying elements, such as Mn and Si;",
    "Normalizing heat treatment;",
    "Quenching and tempering heat treatment;",
    "Cold lamination."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Typical means of obtaining fine-grained structural steels are:",
    answers: ["High content of alloying elements, such as Mn and Si;",
    "Controlled lamination (thermomechanical treatment);",
    "Quenching and tempering heat treatment;",
    "Cold lamination."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"One of the most important properties achieved by a microalloyed steel is:",
    answers: ["Increase in hardness;",
    "Improved machinability;",
    "Increase in the yield strength;",
    "Resistance limit increase."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"One of the most important properties achieved by a microalloyed steel is:",
    answers: ["Increase in hardness;",
    "Improved machinability;",
    "Reduction of the ductile-brittle transition temperature;",
    "Resistance limit increase."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"It is one of the creep mechanisms:",
    answers: ["Grain boundary slippage, which involves diffusion across boundaries;",
    "Formation of internal voids and decarburization by hydrogen effects;",
    "Initiation of cracks in stress concentrators and their subcritical propagation;",
    "Crack initiation in places softened by high temperature and its unstable propagation."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"It is one of the creep mechanisms:",
    answers: ["Sliding and scaling dislocations at high temperatures (dislocation creep);",
    "Formation of internal voids and decarburization by hydrogen effects;",
    "Initiation of cracks in stress concentrators and their subcritical propagation;",
    "Crack initiation in places softened by high temperature and its unstable propagation."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"It is one of the characteristics of heat and creep resistant chromium-molybdenum steels:",
    answers: ["A possible occurrence of the tempering embrittlement when exposed to short periods of time at temperatures between 250 to 600 ºC, resulting in losses of toughness and ductility;",
    "There is also a possibility to use them in cryogenic applications in the same way as ferritic stainless steels;",
    "Work hardening has no influence on the heat and creep resistance of steels;",
    "A significant increase in oxidation and corrosion resistance at elevated temperatures with an increase in Cr content."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"It is one of the characteristics of heat and creep resistant chromium-molybdenum steels:",
    answers: ["A possible occurrence of the tempering embrittlement when exposed to short periods of time at temperatures between 250 to 600 ºC, resulting in losses of toughness and ductility;",
    "There is also a possibility to use them in cryogenic applications in the same way as ferritic stainless steels;",
    "Work hardening has no influence on the heat and creep resistance of steels;",
    "The formation of stable precipitates at elevated temperatures favouring greater creep resistance."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which statement about intergranular corrosion of austenitic stainless steels is correct?",
    answers: ["The corrosion resistance of the matrix (material in the middle of the grain) is lower than the material neighboring the boundary (because the boundaries accumulate more nickel by diffusion).",
    "The intergranular corrosion requires the simultaneous presence of corrosive media and tensile stresses.",
    "A filler metal with a carbon content of less than 0.3% helps minimizing intergranular corrosion (there is little carbon available to form chromium carbides);",
    "As a result of a chromium carbide precipitation, a chromium-depleted zone is formed in the vicinity of grain boundaries."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which statement about intergranular corrosion of austenitic stainless steels is correct?",
    answers: ["The corrosion resistance of the matrix (material in the middle of the grain) is lower than the material neighboring the boundary (because the boundaries accumulate more nickel by diffusion).",
    "The intergranular corrosion requires the simultaneous presence of corrosive media and tensile stresses.",
    "A filler metal with a carbon content of less than 0.3% helps minimizing intergranular corrosion (there is little carbon available to form chromium carbides);",
    "A steel prone to sensitization does not necessarily corrode unless heated during operation at 400 - 600 °C."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the weldability of stainless steels, it can be said that:",
    answers: ["When welding ferritic stainless steels, high heat input must be avoided to prevent excessive grain growth that can induce weld embrittlement;",
    "Duplex stainless steel has its weldability related to the carbon and manganese contents. Higher values of these elements require greater care to pre- and/or post-heating;",
    "Usually, austenitic stainless steels are difficult to weld and require tempering between 600 and 850 °C;",
    "Ferritic stainless steels have good weldability and do not need preheating or PWHT."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the weldability of stainless steels, it can be said that:",
    answers: ["In order to avoid the formation of hot cracks, a delta ferrite content in the fusion zone should be between 5 and 10%;",
    "Duplex stainless steel has its weldability related to the carbon and manganese contents. Higher values of these elements require greater care to pre- and/or post-heating;",
    "Usually, austenitic stainless steels are difficult to weld and require tempering between 600 and 850 °C;",
    "Ferritic stainless steels have good weldability and do not need preheating or PWHT."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the weldability of stainless steels, it can be said that:",
    answers: ["In the prediction of the fusion zone microstructure by the Schaeffler diagram, once the dilution is known, the type of process chosen and the welding conditions become not relevant;",
    "Duplex stainless steel has its weldability related to the carbon and manganese contents. Higher values of these elements require greater care to pre- and/or post-heating;",
    "Usually, austenitic stainless steels are difficult to weld and require tempering between 600 and 850 °C;",
    "Ferritic stainless steels have good weldability and do not need preheating or PWHT."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the weldability of stainless steels, it can be said that:",
    answers: ["The susceptibility to intergranular corrosion of austenitic stainless steels increases with carbon content and with increasing grain size;",
    "Austenitic stainless steels are highly susceptible to cold cracking;",
    "Austenitic stainless steels alloyed by niobium are not susceptible to solidification cracking;",
    "Austenitic stainless steels are not susceptible to hot cracking and to sensitization;"],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the weldability of stainless steels, it can be said that:",
    answers: ["As one of the ways to avoid intergranular corrosion of stainless steels they should stabilized by Nb and/or Ti;",
    "Austenitic stainless steels are highly susceptible to cold cracking;",
    "Austenitic stainless steels alloyed by niobium are not susceptible to solidification cracking;",
    "Austenitic stainless steels are not susceptible to hot cracking and to sensitization;"],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Mark the correct alternative in relation to duplex stainless steels:",
    answers: ["They present a balance of alphagenic and gammagenic elements so that, after na adequate processing, they have a ferrite-austenite microstructure;",
    "They can be weakened during welding by the precipitation of the sigma phase in the HAZ coarse-grained region;",
    "They present an intermediate microstructure between the austenitic and martensitic steel types;",
    "They can be weakened during welding by the precipitation of the X and sigma phases, as well as by the precipitation of carbides and nitrides in the single-pass fusion zone."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"About the properties of copper and its alloys it is correct to say that:",
    answers: ["In general, the mechanical properties of copper improve at low temperatures, which makes it possible to use it in cryogenic applications;",
    "Cu-Sn alloys (bronzes) have better ductility than Cu-Zn alloys (brasses);",
    "Cu-Sn alloys (bronzes) have considerably lower hardness than Cu-Zn alloys (brasses);",
    "Generally, alloying elements such as Nickel, Tin, Zinc and Nitrogen improve the mechanical properties of copper alloys."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Cu-Zn copper alloys (brasses) can be hardened by:",
    answers: ["cold deformation (hardening);",
    "grain refining;",
    "aging heat treatment (precipitation);",
    "phase transformations (through heat treatments)."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"When welding Nickel alloys, attention should be paid to the fact that:",
    answers: ["there is susceptibility to stress corrosion cracking;",
    "there are risks of porosity formation;",
    "TIG (GTAW), MIG/MAG (GMAW) and OFW welding processes are not recommended due to Nickel's high gas dissolution capacity;",
    "the most suitable welding processes are covered electrode (with pure nickel core) and submerged arc (also with pure nickel electrode)."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"When welding Nickel alloys, attention should be paid to the fact that:",
    answers: ["there is susceptibility to cold cracking;",
    "there is susceptibility to solidification cracking;",
    "TIG (GTAW), MIG/MAG (GMAW) and OFW welding processes are not recommended due to Nickel's high gas dissolution capacity;",
    "the most suitable welding processes are covered electrode (with pure nickel core) and submerged arc (also with pure nickel electrode)."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"When welding Nickel alloys, attention should be paid to the fact that:",
    answers: ["there is susceptibility to cold cracking;",
    "the weld pool has low fluidity/high viscosity (risk of lack of penetration);",
    "TIG (GTAW), MIG/MAG (GMAW) and OFW welding processes are not recommended due to Nickel's high gas dissolution capacity;",
    "the most suitable welding processes are covered electrode (with pure nickel core) and submerged arc (also with pure nickel electrode)."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"When welding Nickel alloys, attention should be paid to the fact that:",
    answers: ["there is susceptibility to cold cracking;",
    "cracks may occur due to loss of ductility;",
    "TIG (GTAW), MIG/MAG (GMAW) and OFW welding processes are not recommended due to Nickel's high gas dissolution capacity;",
    "the most suitable welding processes are covered electrode (with pure nickel core) and submerged arc (also with pure nickel electrode)."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"When welding Nickel alloys, attention should be paid to the fact that:",
    answers: ["there is susceptibility to stress corrosion cracking;",
    "larger groove angles (60 – 80 degrees) are needed due to the higher viscosity of the liquid metal (less fluidity);",
    "TIG (GTAW), MIG/MAG (GMAW) and OFW welding processes are not recommended due to Nickel's high gas dissolution capacity;",
    "the most suitable welding processes are covered electrode (with pure nickel core) and submerged arc (also with pure nickel electrode)."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"When welding Nickel alloys, attention should be paid to the fact that:",
    answers: ["preheating is required (up to 150 °C);",
    "interpass temperature should always be kept below 150°C (to minimize potential HAZ problems with corrosion or cracking);",
    "TIG (GTAW), MIG/MAG (GMAW) and OFW welding processes are not recommended due to Nickel's high gas dissolution capacity;",
    "the most suitable welding processes are covered electrode (with pure nickel core) and submerged arc (also with pure nickel electrode)."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the weldability of aluminium and its alloys, it is correct to state that:",
    answers: ["liquation cracking is not a problem for aluminium alloys;",
    "the presence of porosities is a very rare problem, as oxygen combines with Al to form a solid oxide Al2O3;",
    "the wide solidification interval of the alloys can induce solidification cracks;",
    "susceptibility to cracking is low due to a high ductility of aluminium and its alloys."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the weldability of aluminium and its alloys, it is correct to state that:",
    answers: ["cleaning the joint by brushing does not prevent the formation of porosity in the weld, as alumina is formed soon after brushing;",
    "the presence of porosities is a very rare problem, as oxygen combines with Al to form a solid oxide Al2O3;",
    "in the welding of an aluminium alloy hardened by plastic deformation, the HAZ is formed by a region of grain refining and another of grain growth;",
    "susceptibility to cracking is low due to a high ductility of aluminium and its alloys."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the weldability of aluminium and its alloys, it is correct to state that:",
    answers: ["cleaning the joint by brushing does not prevent the formation of porosity in the weld, as alumina is formed soon after brushing;",
    "the presence of porosities is a very rare problem, as oxygen combines with Al to form a solid oxide Al2O3;",
    "the presence of hydrogen in the active zone when welding aluminium and its alloys causes porosity in the weld;",
    "susceptibility to cracking is low due to a high ductility of aluminium and its alloys."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the weldability of aluminium and its alloys, it is correct to state that:",
    answers: ["cleaning the joint by brushing does not prevent the formation of porosity in the weld, as alumina is formed soon after brushing;",
    "the presence of porosities is a very rare problem, as oxygen combines with Al to form a solid oxide Al2O3;",
    "hydrogen cracks in welding aluminium and its alloys are due to a large difference in the solubility of hydrogen in liquid and solid aluminium;",
    "susceptibility to cracking is low due to a high ductility of aluminium and its alloys."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the weldability of aluminium and its alloys, it is correct to state that:",
    answers: ["To avoid the deterioration of the HAZ microstructure of a welded joint of heat-treatable aluminium alloys, heat treatment and plastic deformation are used;",
    "A practical means of determining the width and length of the HAZ is only through weld joint hardness measurements;",
    "For heat-treatable alloys, there is a degradation of the mechanical properties of the base metal located in the HAZ;",
    "For the HAZ of precipitation-hardening alloys, the grain growth is the only critical factor for the decrease in strength."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"One of the most important parameters for efficient thermo-mechanical treatment of steel is:",
    answers: ["controlled hot rolling temperature;",
    "controlled hot rolling temperature, which is higher than in the conventional hot rolling process;",
    "cooling rate, which should be lower to reduce grain size even further;",
    "deformation rate (lower than in the conventional hot rolling process)."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"One of the most important parameters for efficient thermo-mechanical treatment of steel is:",
    answers: ["deformation rate;",
    "controlled hot rolling temperature, which is higher than in the conventional hot rolling process;",
    "cooling rate, which should be lower to reduce grain size even further;",
    "deformation rate (lower than in the conventional hot rolling process)."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"What kind of possible defect is observed in TIG welding of pure titanium?",
    answers: ["Lack of fusion.",
    "Lamellar tearing.",
    "Porosity.",
    "Cold cracking."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"What kind of possible defect is observed in TIG welding of pure titanium?",
    answers: ["Lack of fusion.",
    "Lamellar tearing.",
    "Cold cracking.",
    "Contamination by air gases immediately after welding."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"What causes loss of strength in work-hardened aluminium alloy weldments?",
    answers: ["Overaging of the precipitates.",
    "Increase in the amount of alloying elements that form the precipitates.",
    "Annealing of the cold worked structure.",
    "Reversion (dissolution) of hardening precipitates."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"What causes loss of strength in work-hardened aluminium alloy weldments?",
    answers: ["Overaging of the precipitates.",
    "Increase in the amount of alloying elements that form the precipitates.",
    "Recrystallization and grain growth in the HAZ.",
    "Reversion (dissolution) of hardening precipitates."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"What causes loss of strength in work-hardened aluminium alloy weldments?",
    answers: ["Overaging of the precipitates.",
    "Increase in the amount of alloying elements that form the precipitates.",
    "As cast structure in the weld metal.",
    "Reversion (dissolution) of hardening precipitates."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"1"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the statements listed below is true for welding fine grained structural steel S690QL?",
    answers: ["It can be welded only when the temperature indicating crayon of the preheat temperature changes colour.",
    "It can be welded when the temperature indicating crayons for interpass temperature change colour",
    "It can be welded when the temperature indicating crayons for preheat and interpass temperature change colour.",
    "Using the process 111 with matching filler metal, it is recommended always to preheat the parent material to avoid hydrogen cracking."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"1"},
    {
    question:"Regarding fracture mechanics in welded joints, it is correct to state that:",
    answers: ["Crack nucleation is facilitated by stress concentrators such as discontinuities;",
    "Brittle fracture in structural steel welded joints propagates through the thinner component;",
    "Brittle fracture in structural steel welded joints propagates through the thicker component.",
    "The estimation of the KIC fracture toughness of a material is in the context of Linear Elastic Fracture Mechanics."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the dimensioning of a welded joint under dynamic loading according to Eurocode3, Part 1.9, it is correct to state that:",
    answers: ["Only the average stress level to which the joint is subjected is considered, disregarding the stress range;",
    "Only the stress range to which the joint is subjected is considered, disregarding the average stress level;",
    "The stress range and the stress average level to which the joint is submitted are considered;",
    "The average stress level and the maximum predicted stress are considered."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the methods of dimensioning welded joints, it is correct to state that:",
    answers: ["In the Permissible Stress method, a safety factor equal to 3 is always used, to ensure the weldment strength;",
    "The Limit States method works with large plastic deformations by applying Fracture Mechanics;",
    "The high value of the safety factor applied to cast materials is due to the risk of generating, during solidification, a greater number of defects that can propagate rapidly even under low stresses.",
    "In the Limit States Method, only one safety factor is applied to the resistances and both the resistances and the actions are worked with average values."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the methods of dimensioning welded joints, it is correct to state that:",
    answers: ["In the Permissible Stress method, a safety factor equal to 3 is always used, to ensure the weldment strength;",
    "The Limit States method works with large plastic deformations by applying Fracture Mechanics;",
    "Conventional designs are, in general, based on the philosophy of avoiding the occurrence of widespread plastic collapse, so they only use the yield point of the material.",
    "In the Permissible Stress Method, partial safety factors are applied for the actions and resistances."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the methods of dimensioning welded joints, it is correct to state that:",
    answers: ["In the Permissible Stress method, a safety factor equal to 3 is always used, to ensure the weldment strength;",
    "The Limit States method works with large plastic deformations by applying Fracture Mechanics;",
    "In conventional designs, the selection of a material is generally made by comparing the design stress, multiplied by a factor of safety, with the yield strength of the material.",
    "In the Limit States Method, only one safety factor is applied to the resistances and both the resistances and the actions are worked with average values."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the methods of dimensioning welded joints, it is correct to state that:",
    answers: ["In the Permissible Stress method, a safety factor equal to 3 is always used, to ensure the weldment strength;",
    "The Limit States method works with large plastic deformations by applying Fracture Mechanics;",
    "In the Permissible Stress Method, only one safety factor is applied to the resistances and both the resistances and the actions are worked with average values;",
    "In the Permissible Stress Method, partial safety factors are applied for the actions and resistances."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the methods of dimensioning welded joints, it is correct to state that:",
    answers: ["In the Permissible Stress method, a safety factor equal to 3 is always used, to ensure the weldment strength;",
    "The Limit States method works with large plastic deformations by applying Fracture Mechanics;",
    "In the Limit States Method, partial safety factors are applied for actions and resistances;",
    "In the Limit States Method, only one safety factor is applied to the resistances and both the resistances and the actions are worked with average values."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"About the stress tensor it is correct to say:",
    answers: ["The stress tensor is not symmetrical;",
    "The stress tensor can be used to predict the plastic deformations of a body subjected to a three-dimensional load;",
    "The stress tensor is a 3x3 matrix where all the stresses acting on the infinitesimal element are placed;",
    "The stress tensor is a 3x3x3 matrix where all the stresses acting on the infinitesimal element are placed;"],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"In which fatigue test diagram, on the vertical axis is shown the alternating stress, while on the horizontal axis is shown the mean stress?",
    answers: ["Palmgren-Miner diagram. ",
    "Coulomb's diagram. ",
    "Von Mises diagram.",
    "Goodman's diagram. "],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"In a welded joint that will be subjected to fatigue, it is recommended to:",
    answers: ["use materials of very high mechanical resistance, with a small plastic region;",
    "to avoid joint corrosion;",
    "apply the TIG dressing technique for total remelting of the weld bead, with a high level of current to guarantee the weld full penetration;",
    "add secondary members, such as brackets, fitting etc, to reinforce the structure."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the design of a dynamically loaded welded joint, it is correct to state that:",
    answers: ["the safe-life design philosophy should be applied;",
    "according to Eurocode 3, Part 1.9, for design purposes, only the average level of active stresses to which the joint is submitted is considered, disregarding the stress range;",
    "the fatigue strength of welded joints depends on the static strength of the material;",
    "the joint must be dimensioned always for infinite life (above 108 cycles)."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the design of a dynamically loaded welded joint, it is correct to state that:",
    answers: ["according to Eurocode 3, Part 1.9, for the purpose of dimensioning, only the acting stress range to which the joint is submitted is considered, disregarding the average stress level;",
    "according to Eurocode 3, Part 1.9, for design purposes, only the average level of active stresses to which the joint is submitted is considered, disregarding the stress range;",
    "the fatigue strength of welded joints depends on the static strength of the material;",
    "the joint must be dimensioned always for infinite life (above 108 cycles)."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"About the mechanical properties of aluminum alloys, it is correct to say that:",
    answers: ["Aluminium alloys have higher tensile strength compared to pure aluminum, but lower toughness and ductility;",
    "In welding heat-treatable aluminium alloys, there is no degradation of the HAZ metal properties;",
    "At low temperatures, aluminium's strength increases without loss of ductility and toughness, which is the reason for its increasing use in cryogenic applications;",
    "When dimensioning an aluminium welded joint, only the strength of the deposited weld metal must be taken into account for the design."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"KIc values are:",
    answers: ["low for ductile materials;",
    "low for fragile materials;",
    "higher for fragile materials;",
    "independent of the brittleness/ductility of the materials, as they mainly depend on the yield strength."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the Linear Elastic Fracture Mechanics (LEFM), it can be said that:",
    answers: ["The LEFM is valid for cases of large-scale plastic deformation.",
    "Some examples of materials that can be analysed by LEFM are aluminium alloys, copper alloys, nickel alloys and austenitic stainless steels;",
    "Before unstable propagation, extensive stable tearing occurs;",
    "The LEFM is applicable when plastic flow is limited to a small region near the crack tip."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the Linear Elastic Fracture Mechanics (LEFM), it can be said that:",
    answers: ["The LEFM is valid for cases of large-scale plastic deformation.",
    "Before unstable propagation, extensive stable tearing occurs;",
    "Some examples of materials that can be analysed by LEFM are aluminium alloys, copper alloys, nickel alloys and austenitic stainless steels;",
    "Some examples of materials that can be analysed by the LEFM are: high-strength steels, cold-formed stainless steels, between others."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the Linear Elastic Fracture Mechanics (LEFM), it can be said that:",
    answers: ["The LEFM is valid for cases of large-scale plastic deformation.",
    "Some examples of materials that can be analysed by LEFM are aluminium alloys, copper alloys, nickel alloys and austenitic stainless steels;",
    "Before unstable propagation, extensive stable tearing occurs;",
    "For the fracture to occur, it is necessary that the length of the defect is sufficient to prevent the effects of the microstructure from affecting its propagation. Which depends on the grain size of the material."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the Linear Elastic Fracture Mechanics (LEFM), it can be said that:",
    answers: ["The LEFM is valid for cases of large-scale plastic deformation.",
    "Some examples of materials that can be analysed by LEFM are aluminium alloys, copper alloys, nickel alloys and austenitic stainless steels;",
    "Before unstable propagation, extensive stable tearing occurs;",
    "The LEFM is a methodology for analysing planar crack-type defects to be used in situations where the possibility of plastic deformation around the crack front is small."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the Linear Elastic Fracture Mechanics (LEFM), it can be said that:",
    answers: ["The LEFM is valid for cases of large-scale plastic deformation.",
    "Some examples of materials that can be analysed by LEFM are aluminium alloys, copper alloys, nickel alloys and austenitic stainless steels;",
    "Before unstable propagation, extensive stable tearing occurs;",
    "Fracture toughness is a material intrinsic property, being defined as the resistance to the crack propagation under Plane Stress State;"],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"The design methods that can be used for designing welded joints is:",
    answers: ["Limit stress method;",
    "Method of admissible states;",
    "Nominal stress method;",
    "Permissible stress method."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"The design methods that can be used for designing welded joints is:",
    answers: ["Limit stress method;",
    "Method of admissible states;",
    "Nominal stress method;",
    "Limit state method;"],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"The CTOD test is used:",
    answers: ["in materials of high mechanical strength, where the concepts of linear-elastic fracture mechanics predominate, as well as in ductile materials, where the elastic-plastic behaviour is present;",
    "only when the material behaves perfectly elastic;",
    "only when the material has a rupture strength greater than 500 N/mm2;",
    "as an alternative to the Charpy test."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"2"
    },
    {
    question:"Which is the highest open circuit voltage (peak value) allowed for welding with direct current for environment without increased hazard of electric shock (as per IEC-60974-1)?",
    answers: ["48 V",
    "68 V",
    "80 V",
    "113 V"],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Which standard ISO describes the welding procedure specification (WPS)?",
    answers: ["EN ISO 9606-2",
    "EN ISO 15611",
    "EN ISO 15614-1",
    "EN ISO 15609-1"],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"NOT an objective of ISO 9001 (Quality Management System, Requirements):",
    answers: ["To enable organizations to identify, monitor and meet customer requirements and applicable regulatory requirements;",
    "To advance in the pursuit of continuous improvement of the organization and customer satisfaction;",
    "To demonstrate the organization's ability to provide the best possible quality product even at high cost;",
    "\"To implement the \"\"process approach\"\", which allows continuous improvement (of processes) based on the conversion of inputs into output.\""],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following destructive tests can be used for welding procedure qualification (WPS)?",
    answers: ["Hardness test.",
    "Fracture test.",
    "Charpy test.",
    "Fatigue test."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following destructive tests can be used for welding procedure qualification (WPS)?",
    answers: ["Hardness test.",
    "Fracture test.",
    "Bending test.",
    "Fatigue test."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of the following destructive tests can be used for welding procedure qualification (WPS)?",
    answers: ["Hardness test.",
    "Fracture test.",
    "Tensile test.",
    "Fatigue test."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"The chronological sequence that must be followed in welding procedure qualifications is as follows:",
    answers: ["Preliminary WPS; welding the test piece; testing; RQPS + Qualified WPS + Qualified welder who welded the test piece.",
    "Preparation of preliminary WPS; qualification of the welder who will weld the test piece; welding the test piece; testing; RQPS + Qualified WPS.",
    "Welding the test piece; preparation of preliminary WPS; testing; RQPS + qualified WPS + qualified welder who welded the test piece.",
    "Qualified WPS; welding test piece; testing; RQPS + qualified welder who welded the test piece."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Generally, the most Intense ultraviolet light is produced when:",
    answers: ["welding carbon steel using MMA/SMAW process.",
    "welding carbon steel using TIG or MIG/MAG welding.",
    "welding aluminium using TIG or MIG/MAG welding.",
    "welding aluminium using MMA/SMAW process."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Based on the typical activities of an international welding inspector and an international welding engineer, one can say that:",
    answers: ["The inspector is responsible for the production, while the engineer for its control in accordance with standards;",
    "The engineer is the one who qualifies welders, and it is up to the inspector to ensure that the personnel is qualified;",
    "The functions and attributions of both are the same, differing only in the need for a higher education for the engineer, a fact that can be compensated by a greater experience for an inspector.",
    "The engineer is responsible for planning production, elaborating welding procedures, etc., but he/she is not fully qualified to qualify procedures based on standards."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the education, duties and activities of engineers and welding inspectors, it is correct to say:",
    answers: ["The welding inspector is not required to have a higher education, as he/she is only required to follow the rules (compliance);",
    "The welding inspector must always report to a welding engineer;",
    "The welding engineer is not required to have a higher education, as his/her activities are governed by standards;",
    "The welding inspector must have a detailed and complete knowledge of welding as it is he who inspects the welding engineer's activities."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the education, duties and activities of engineers and welding inspectors, it is correct to say:",
    answers: ["It is up to the engineer to select welding processes and techniques, equipment and consumables, aiming at economic, technical and safety optimization.",
    "The welding inspector must always report to a welding engineer;",
    "The welding engineer is not required to have a higher education, as his/her activities are governed by standards;",
    "It is up to the engineer to select welding processes, equipment and consumables, but the results of selection must be approved by the welding inspector."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"What is the fundamental difference between the inspection of new equipment and the inspection of in-service equipment?",
    answers: ["In-service inspection of pressure vessels doesn’t require a qualification, which is obligatory during vessel fabrication.",
    "In-service inspection requires, in many situations, the identification of the damage and its extent, in addition to allowing the monitoring of its progression in operation.",
    "Inspection of in-service equipment is done by comparing the current NDT results with that of the equipment manufacture.",
    "There are practically no differences. The same NDTs are used with the same acceptance criteria. The only difference is that, as expected, in-service equipment has more defects."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"What is the fundamental difference between the inspection of new equipment and the inspection of in-service equipment?",
    answers: ["In-service inspection of pressure vessels doesn’t require a qualification, which is obligatory during vessel fabrication.",
    "Factory inspection (of new equipment) uses standard/norm acceptance criteria to define repairs.",
    "Inspection of in-service equipment is done by comparing the current NDT results with that of the equipment manufacture.",
    "There are practically no differences. The same NDTs are used with the same acceptance criteria. The only difference is that, as expected, in-service equipment has more defects."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"What is the fundamental difference between the inspection of new equipment and the inspection of in-service equipment?",
    answers: ["In-service inspection of pressure vessels doesn’t require a qualification, which is obligatory during vessel fabrication.",
    "In-service inspection does not have acceptance standards and depends on the application of evaluation criteria and procedures to define repairs.",
    "Inspection of in-service equipment is done by comparing the current NDT results with that of the equipment manufacture.",
    "There are practically no differences. The same NDTs are used with the same acceptance criteria. The only difference is that, as expected, in-service equipment has more defects."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"The Phased Array technique of the ultrasonic testing:",
    answers: ["uses 45- and 70-degree beam angles;",
    "uses four transducers to improve sensitivity;",
    "uses longitudinal and transverse waves to increase the precision in the dimensioning of imperfections;",
    "offers high flexibility for manipulation of the ultrasonic beam."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Why does the ToFD technique stand out from other ultrasonic testing methods?",
    answers: ["It has a high signal-to-noise ratio.",
    "It offers greater accuracy for dimensioning the length of discontinuities.",
    "It offers greater precision for dimensioning the height of discontinuities.",
    "It has excellent detectability for near-surface discontinuities."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Why does the ToFD technique stand out from other ultrasonic testing methods?",
    answers: ["It has a high signal-to-noise ratio.",
    "It offers greater accuracy for dimensioning the length of discontinuities.",
    "It is sensitive to all discontinuities regardless of the orientation.",
    "It has excellent detectability for near-surface discontinuities."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"One of the disadvantages of the ToFD ultrasonic testing technique is that:",
    answers: ["the accuracy for dimensioning the height of discontinuities is low;",
    "there is no way to store digitally the ToFD results;",
    "the access on both side of the weld is required;",
    "it is sensitive only to discontinuities oriented perpendicularly to the ultrasonic beam."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"The quality system (QS) certification concept means:",
    answers: ["verification of the manufacturer’s QS by an authorized impartial organisation (third party) from the aspect of fulfilment of the requirements of respective standard;",
    "verification of the manufacturer’s QS by a customer trusted representative from the aspect of its competence and ability to deliver products of required quality;",
    "verification of the QS by the company management itself evaluating its competence to achieve required quality objectives",
    "verification of the company’s QS by the national accreditation authority."],
    correctAnswer:"0",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"One of the non-destructive methods for measuring residual welding stresses is:",
    answers: ["Inspection by eddy currents;",
    "X-ray diffraction method;",
    "Blind hole drilling technique;",
    "Sectioning method."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"One of the non-destructive methods for measuring residual welding stresses is:",
    answers: ["Inspection by eddy currents;",
    "Ultrasonic analysis;",
    "Blind hole drilling technique;",
    "Sectioning method."],
    correctAnswer:"1",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of these alternatives describes the principle of measuring residual welding stresses by ultrasonic testing?",
    answers: ["Measuring the resistance of the material to the propagation of the ultrasonic wave which (propagation) depends on the level of stress in the material.",
    "Measuring the ultrasonic wave attenuation which (attenuation) depends on the stresses level in the material.",
    "Measuring the ultrasonic noises in the material whose level depends on the level of stresses in the material.",
    "Measuring changes in ultrasonic wave velocity, as there is an almost linear relationship between the ultrasonic wave velocity and an applied stress."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Which of these alternatives describes the principle of measuring residual welding stresses by the X-ray diffraction method?",
    answers: ["Measuring the material's resistance to X-ray propagation which (propagation) depends on the stress level in the material.",
    "Measuring the attenuation of the X-ray beam in the material which (attenuation) depends on the level of stresses in the material.",
    "Measuring the variation of distances between atoms and relating it to the stresses acting on the material.",
    "Measuring the variation of distances between crystalline planes and relating it to the stresses acting on the material."],
    correctAnswer:"3",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the FAD (Failure Assessment Diagram), it is correct to say that:",
    answers: ["A flaw can be analysed by calculating Kr and Lr independently and plotting the result on a FAD. If the point lies outside the failure assessment line (FAL), it can be considered safe, if within it is potentially unsafe. ",
    "This diagram is used for the critical evaluation of components with discontinuities that meet the quality criteria.",
    "The FAD makes it possible to assess the occurrence of brittle fracture or plastic collapse of the structure.",
    " A point lying on the FAL (failure assessment line) represents a safe condition, with no threat to the structure integrity."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the FAD (Failure Assessment Diagram), it is correct to say that:",
    answers: ["A flaw can be analysed by calculating Kr and Lr independently and plotting the result on a FAD. If the point lies outside the failure assessment line (FAL), it can be considered safe, if within it is potentially unsafe. ",
    "The FAD allows evaluating the occurrence of only brittle fracture of the structure.",
    "This diagram is used for the critical evaluation of welded components with planar discontinuities.",
    " A point lying on the FAL (failure assessment line) represents a safe condition, with no threat to the structure integrity."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the FAD (Failure Assessment Diagram), it is correct to say that:",
    answers: ["A flaw can be analysed by calculating Kr and Lr independently and plotting the result on a FAD. If the point lies outside the failure assessment line (FAL), it can be considered safe, if within it is potentially unsafe. ",
    "The FAD allows evaluating the occurrence of only brittle fracture of the structure.",
    "The FAD is based on the Kr and Lr factors which measure a fracture risk and a risk of a plastic collapse, respectively.",
    "The Lr axis takes into account all factors influencing crack driving force: primary stresses (from self-weight, pressure, live load), secondary stresses (typically welding residual stresses), thermal stresses and local stress concentrations."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the FAD (Failure Assessment Diagram), it is correct to say that:",
    answers: ["This diagram is used for the critical evaluation of components with discontinuities that meet the quality criteria.",
    "The FAD allows evaluating the occurrence of only brittle fracture of the structure.",
    "A flaw can be analysed by calculating Kr and Lr independently and plotting the result on a FAD. If the point lies within the failure assessment line (FAL), it can be considered safe, if outside it is potentially unsafe. ",
    " A point lying on the FAL (failure assessment line) represents a safe condition, with no threat to the structure integrity."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the FAD (Failure Assessment Diagram), it is correct to say that:",
    answers: ["A flaw can be analysed by calculating Kr and Lr independently and plotting the result on a FAD. If the point lies outside the failure assessment line (FAL), it can be considered safe, if within it is potentially unsafe. ",
    "The FAD allows evaluating the occurrence of only brittle fracture of the structure.",
    "A FAD can be applied for evaluation of the fracture strength of cracked structures.",
    "The Lr axis takes into account all factors influencing crack driving force: primary stresses (from self-weight, pressure, live load), secondary stresses (typically welding residual stresses), thermal stresses and stress concentrations."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"3"
    },
    {
    question:"Regarding the FAD (Failure Assessment Diagram), it is correct to say that:",
    answers: ["This diagram is used for the critical evaluation of components with discontinuities that meet the quality criteria.",
    "The FAD allows evaluating the occurrence of only brittle fracture of the structure.",
    "An increased load or larger crack size (crack propagation) will move the assessment point along the loading path towards the failure assessment line (FAL).",
    " A point lying on the FAL (failure assessment line) represents a safe condition, with no threat to the structure integrity."],
    correctAnswer:"2",
    subject:"3"}];